Register of the Milton Genecin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Internal Documents, 1937-1983; 11-19 (Box 11-19: 6)
  - 1957 (Folder 12-13:)
    - May 14-December (Folder 13: 1)
      Includes convention documents; reports and discussion material on regroupment; "Resolution on the Negro Struggle" by Richard Fraser; documents on British section; "Memorandum on the Communist Party"; resolution on Sputnik; "The Present Political Conjuncture in the United States and the Tasks of the Party"; "The Present Stage of the International Unity Discussion"
  - 1958 (Folder 13: 2)
    Includes minutes; reports and discussion material on unified election tickets; "Platform of the Independent-Socialist Party"; "Resolution on the Little Rock Crisis" by Richard Fraser
  - 1959 (Folder 13: 3)
    Includes minutes; discussion material and draft resolutions on Chinese communes by Arne Swabeck, Frank Glass, Peng Shu-tse, Dan Roberts, Myra Tanner Weiss and others; "A Proposal for an Abolition Party" by Frank Glass and George Breitman; "The 1959 Situation in the Socialist Labour League" by Peter Cadogan; other statements and open letters by Peter Fryer and others re British section
  - 1960 (Folder 13: 4)
    Includes "Draft Theses on the Cuban Revolution"; "The Cuban Revolution and Marxist Theory" by Shane Mage and others; "The Character of the New Cuban Government" by Joseph Hansen; "Memorandum on the Principled Groundwork of Our Tactics and Slogans in the Struggle against Imperialist War" by Murry Weiss; discussion material on split within Fourth International
  - 1961 (Folder 13: 5)
    Includes minutes; amended constitution; circulated correspondence with Socialist Labour League of Great Britain; Socialist Labour League resolutions; report on International Committee; "The Struggle between the Socialist and Capitalist Camps"; statement re party-youth relations by Tim Wohlforth and others
  - 1962 (Folder 14: 1)
    Includes minutes; "The Chinese Revolution: Its Character and Development" by Arne Swabeck and Frank Glass; "Our China Policy" and "Where I Differ with Comrade Swabeck on the China Question" by Frank Glass; "On the Twentieth Anniversary of the Transitional Program" by S. Y. Wang; "In Defense of a Revolutionary Perspective" by Joyce Cowley and others; circulated correspondence with Socialist Labour League of Great Britain; "Draft Reply to SLL" by George Novack; "Problems of the Fourth International, and the Next Steps"; "Report on House Un-American Activities Committee Hearings" by Oscar Coover
  - 1963 (Folder 14: 2-3)
    - February-June (Folder 14: 2)
      Includes "Considerations on the World Crisis of Stalinism and Our Attitude Toward It"; "For Early Reunification of the World Trotskyist Movement"; "The Sino-Soviet Dispute"; "The Rebuilding of the Fourth International" by the Reorganized Minority Tendency; "Preparing for the Next Wave of Radicalism in the United States"; "Marxism and the Sino-Soviet Dispute" by Arne Swabeck; discussion material on China; "Toward Rebirth of the Fourth International" by the Minority Tendency
    - July-December (Folder 14: 3)
      Includes convention documents; minutes; discussion material on China; "Report on Internal Party Situation" by Farrell Dobbs; "Draft Resolution on the Organizational Character of the SWP"; "Freedom Now: The New Stage in the Struggle for Negro Emancipation and the Tasks of the SWP"; "The Decline of American Imperialism and the Tasks of the SWP" by the Reorganized Minority Tendency
  - 1964 (Folder 14: 4)
    Includes minutes; "Khrushchev Ouster" by Farrell Dobbs; United Secretariat statement on internal situation
  - 1965 (Folder 14: 5)
    Includes minutes; "Statutes of the Fourth International"; reports on publications and on antiwar movement
  - 1966 (Folder 15: 1)
    Includes "Statement of Resignation" by Kirk-Kaye group and "Political Committee Statement on the Kirk-Kaye Split"; "Postwar Trends and Short-Run Prospects of the U.S. Economy" by Herbert Porter; discussion material on antiwar movement; "Report on the Black Panther Party" by Betsey Stone; circulated correspondence by Arne Swabeck and others re China; "Defending the Revolutionary Party and Its Perspectives" (collected documents from 1952-1953 factional struggle)
  - 1967 (Folder 15: 2)
    Includes minutes; amended constitution; "Party Policy on the Chinese Question and in the Antiwar Movement" by Arne Swabeck; resignation statement of Hildegarde Swabeck; report on European sections; circulated correspondence with Socialist Labour League of Great Britain
  - 1968 (Folder 15: 3)
    Includes report on Peace and Freedom Party by Tom Kerry; "The World Situation at the Beginning of 1968"
  - 1969 (Folder 15: 4)
    Includes amended constitution; minutes
  - 1970 (Folder 15: 5)
    Includes minutes; report on membership policy re homosexuality by Jack Barnes; report on auto workers strike by Tom Kerry; Socialist Activists and Educational Conference reports; circulated documents from International Marxist Group of Great Britain
  - 1971 (Folder 15-16:)
    - February-June (Folder 15: 6)
      Includes minutes; membership statistics; discussion material re United Secretariat
    - July-November (Folder 16: 1)
      Includes minutes; convention documents; amended constitution; "Memorandum on the Leadership Question" by Farrell Dobbs; circulated correspondence with Proletarian Orientation Tendency and Communist Tendency
  - 1972 (Folder 16:)
    - January-May (Folder 16: 2)
      Includes circulated materials re Latin America; minutes; "Report of the Fact-Finding Commission of the United Secretariat on the Internal Situation within the International Marxist Group, British Section of the Fourth International"; "A Contribution to the Discussion of the Leadership Question" by George Breitman; membership statistics
    - August-December (Folder 16: 3)
      Includes instructional program materials; minutes; reports on tours of Europe by Gerry Foley and Dan Rosenshine; circulated materials re Latin America and British section
  - 1973 (Folder 16-17:)
    - January-April (Folder 16: 4)
      Includes discussion material re Communist Party; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; minutes; membership and publications statistics
    - May-September (Folder 17: 1)
      Includes circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; minutes; circulated documents re Internationalist Tendency; convention documents; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; "Declaration of the Compass Tendency"
    - October-December (Folder 17: 2)
      Includes Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; "Draft of World Political Resolution"; minutes; circulated exchange re gay liberation movement
  - 1974 (Folder 17-18:)
    - January-June (Folder 17: 3)
      Includes circulated legal documents re SWP lawsuit against U.S. Attorney General and others; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; minutes; circulated exchange re Coalition of Labor Union Women; circulated exchange with and re Internationalist Tendency; circulated exchanges re critical support to Communist Party; membership, financial and publication statistics
    - July-September (Folder 17: 4)
      Includes minutes; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; circulated exchange with and re Internationalist Tendency
    - October-December (Folder 18: 1)
      Includes Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchange re international sections and with United Secretariat
  - 1975 (Folder 18:)
    - January-April 20 (Folder 18: 2)
      Includes Young Socialist Alliance constitution; minutes; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; "Organizing the YSA: Financial Handbook"; circulated documents re Communist Party; "The Fight for Black Liberation, the Current Stage and Its Tasks"
    - April 22-June (Folder 18: 3)
      Includes minutes; "The Decline of American Capitalism: Prospects for a Socialist Revolution"; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat
    - July-November (Folder 18: 4)
      Includes convention documents; Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges re international sections and with United Secretariat; minutes; circulated exchange with Organizing Committee for Reconstruction of the Fourth International; "The Key Issues of the Portuguese Revolution"
  - 1976 (Folder 18: 5)
    Includes Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchange with United Secretariat: "Proposal on the Structure and Organization of the Party Leadership" by Mary-Alice Waters
  - 1977 (Folder 19: 1)
    Includes Leninist-Trotskyist Faction circulated documents; circulated exchanges with United Secretariat, Bolshevik Tendency, Workers Revolutionary Party of Great Britain and other international groups; material re critical support of Communist Party election candidate
  - 1978 (Folder 19: 2)
    Committee for a Revolutionary Socialist Party circulated documents
  - 1980 (Folder 19: 3)
    Open letter by Myra Tanner Weiss; Socialist Educational and Activists Conference program
  - 1981 (Folder 19: 4)
    Document re air controllers strike; legal document re SWP lawsuit against U.S. Attorney General and others
  - 1983 (Folder 19: 5)
    "Deepening the Turn in the Rail Industry" by Kathe Latham and Byron Ackerman
- Internal Bulletins, 1937-1984; 19-41 (Box 19-41:)
  Socialist Workers Party and related internal bulletins
  Arranged by title
  - Internal Bulletin of Organizing Committee of the Socialist Party Convention (SWP founding convention). 1937. No. 5 (Folder 19: 6)
  - Pre-Plenum Discussion Bulletin (SWP). 1940. Vol. 3 no. 2 (Folder 19: 7)
  - Internal Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 19-22:)
    - 1938. No. 1-2, 4-5, 7 (Folder 19: 8)
    - 1939. No. 9-10; vol. 2 no. 1-3, 5 (Folder 19: 9)
    - 1940. Vol. 2 no. 6-7, 10, 12 (Folder 19: 10)
    - 1942. Vol. 4 no. 1, 3 (Folder 19: 11)
    - 1943. Vol. 5 no. 1 (Folder 19: 12)
    - 1944 (Folder 20: 1-2)
      - Vol. 6 no. 1, 3-7 (Folder 20: 1)
      - Vol. 6 no. 9-10, 12-13 (Folder 20: 2)
    - 1945. Vol. 7 no. 1-3, 5, 7-9, 11-12 (Folder 20: 3)
    - 1946. Vol. 8 no. 1, 5, 7-9, 12 (Folder 20: 4)
    - 1947. Vol. 9 no. 2-5, 7 (Folder 21: 1)
    - 1948. Vol. 10 no. 1-6 (Folder 21: 2)
    - 1949. Vol. 11 no. 1-5 (Folder 21: 3)
    - 1950. Vol. 12 no. 1-3 (Folder 21: 4)
    - 1951. Vol. 13 no. 1 (Folder 21: 5)
    - 1952. Vol. 14 no. 1 (Folder 21: 6)
    - 1953 (Folder 21-22:)
      - Vol. 15 no. 4-7 (Folder 21: 7)
      - Vol. 15 no. 8-11 (Folder 22: 1)
      - Vol. 15 no. 12-15 (Folder 22: 2)
      - Vol. 15 no. 16-17, 19-20 (Folder 22: 3)
    - 1954. Vol. 16 no. 1-2 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Discussion Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 23-32:)
    - 1950. No. 1-4 (Folder 23: 1)
    - 1951. No. 6, 8-9 (Folder 23: 2)
    - 1952. No. 10 (Folder 23: 3)
    - 1953. No. A-12 (Folder 23: 4)
    - 1954 (Folder 23: 5-6)
      - No. A-13-A-17, A-19 (Folder 23: 5)
      - No. A-20-A-22, A-24, A-26 (Folder 23: 6)
    - 1955. No. A-27, A-29-A-31, A-33 (Folder 24: 1)
    - 1956. Vol. 17 no. 1-4 (Folder 24: 2)
    - 1959 (Folder 24: 3-4)
      - Vol. 18 no. 1-8 (Folder 24: 3)
      - Vol. 18 no. 9-10, 10 [sic], 11-14 (Folder 24: 4)
    - 1958. Vol. 19 no. 2-3 (Folder 24: 5)
    - 1959 (Folder 24-25:)
      - Vol. 20 no. 1-7 (Folder 24: 6)
      - Vol. 20 no. 8-10 (Folder 25: 1)
      - Vol. 20 no. 11-16 (Folder 25: 2)
    - 1960. Vol. 21 no. 1-4 (Folder 25: 3)
    - 1961 (Folder 25-26:)
      - Vol. 22 no. 1-6 (Folder 25: 4)
      - Vol. 22 no. 7-12 (Folder 25: 5)
      - Vol. 22 no. 13-19 (Folder 26: 1)
    - 1962 (Folder 26:)
      - Vol. 23 no. 1, 3-6 (Folder 26: 2)
      - Vol. 23 no. 7-10 (Folder 26: 3)
    - 1963 (Folder 26-27:)
      - Vol. 24 no. 1-10 (Folder 26: 4)
      - Vol. 24 no. 11-20 (Folder 27: 1)
      - Vol. 24 no. 21-29 (Folder 27: 2)
      - Vol. 24 no. 30-34 (Folder 27: 3)
    - 1965 (Folder 27-28:)
      - Vol. 25 no. 1-4, 6-7 (Folder 27: 4)
      - Vol. 25 no. 8-11 (Folder 28: 1)
      - Vol. 25 no. 12-14, unnumbered [15], 16 (Folder 28: 2)
    - 1967 (Folder 28:)
      - Vol. 26 no. 1-8 (Folder 28: 3)
      - Vol. 26 no. 9-12 (Folder 28: 4)
    - 1969. Vol. 27 no. 2-13 (Folder 28: 5)
    - 1970. Vol. 28 no. 1 (Folder 28: 6)
    - 1971 (Folder 29:)
      - Vol. 29 no. 1-17 (Folder 29: 1)
      - Vol. 29 no. 18-28 (Folder 29: 2)
    - 1972. Vol. 30 no. 1-9 (Folder 29: 3)
    - 1977 (Folder 29:)
      - Vol. 35 no. 1-9 (Folder 29: 4)
      - Vol. 35 no. 10-16 (Folder 29: 5)
    - 1979 (Folder 31:)
      - Vol. 36 no. 1-14 (Folder 31: 1)
      - Vol. 36 no. 15-23 (Folder 31: 2)
    - 1981 (Folder 31-32:)
      - Vol. 37 no. 1-2, 2 corrected, 3-10 (Folder 31: 3)
      - Vol. 37 no. 11-19 (Folder 31: 4)
      - Vol. 37 no. 20-26 (Folder 32: 1)
    - 1984. Vol. 38 no. 1 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Internal Information Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 32-34:)
    - 1964. January no. 1-2, February no. 1, April no. 1-2 (Folder 32: 3)
    - 1966. July (Folder 32: 4)
    - 1967. January, December no. [1]-2 (Folder 32: 5)
    - 1968. June, July (Folder 32: 6)
    - 1969. April no. [1]-2, June, no. 4-8 (Folder 32: 7)
    - 1970. No. 1-6 (Folder 32: 8)
    - 1971. No. 1-7 (Folder 32: 9)
    - 1972. No. 1, 3-5 (Folder 33: 1)
    - 1973. No. 1-10 (Folder 33: 2)
    - 1974. No. 1-9 (Folder 33: 3)
    - 1975. No. 1 (Folder 33: 4)
    - 1976. No. 1-6, 8-15 (Folder 33: 5)
    - 1977. No. 1-8 (Folder 33: 6)
    - 1979. No. 1 (Folder 33: 7)
    - 1981. No. 1 (Folder 33: 8)
    - 1983. No. 1 (Folder 34: 1)
    - 1984. No. 1 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Information Bulletin (SWP). 1984. No. 2 (Folder 34: 3)
  - International Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 34:)
    - 1942. Vol. 2 no. 1, 3 (Folder 34: 4)
    - 1945. Vol. 3 no. 1 (Folder 34: 5)
  - International Information Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 34-36:)
    - 1946. Vol. 1 no. 1 (Folder 34: 6)
    - 1947. Vol. 1 no. 2 (Folder 34: 7)
    - 1949. June, December (Folder 34: 8)
    - 1950. May, September (two issues) (Folder 34: 9)
    - 1951. January, March, April, July, August, December (Folder 34: 10)
    - 1952 (Folder 34-35:)
      - February, March, April, June (Folder 34: 11)
      - October, November, December (Folder 35: 1)
    - 1953. January, September (Folder 35: 2)
    - 1954. January (Folder 35: 3)
    - 1961. March, April (Folder 35: 4)
    - 1962. No. 1 (Folder 35: 5)
    - 1963. April no. 1, May no. 1, July no. 1, August no. 1 (Folder 35: 6)
    - 1964. May no. 1 (Folder 35: 7)
    - 1965. February no. 1, August no. 1-2, November no. 1, December no. 1 (Folder 35: 8)
    - 1966. June (two issues), July, August (Folder 35: 9)
    - 1968. No. 1, April, October (Folder 36: 1)
    - 1969. No. 1-10 (Folder 36: 2)
    - 1970. No. 1-7 (Folder 36: 3)
    - 1971. No. 1-6 (Folder 36: 4)
    - 1972. No. 1-5 (Folder 36: 5)
    - Reprints from 1968-1971 issues. Six issues, including Discussion on China, Discussion on Europe, Discussion on Latin America (Folder 36: 6)
  - International Internal Discussion Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 37-38:)
    - 1973 (Folder 37: 1-2)
      - Vol. 10 no. 1-12 (Folder 37: 1)
      - Vol. 10 no. 14-21, 23-26 (Folder 37: 2)
    - 1974. Vol. 11 no. 1-5 (Folder 37: 3)
    - 1975. Vol. 12 no. 1-3 (Folder 37: 4)
    - 1976. Vol. 13 no. 3-5, 8-9 (Folder 37: 5)
    - 1977. Vol. 14 no. 1-8 (Folder 37: 6)
    - 1978. Vol. 15 no. 1-7 (Folder 37: 7)
    - 1979. Vol. 16 no. 1-2, 5-9 (Folder 38: 1)
    - 1980. Vol. 17 no. 1 (Folder 38: 2)
    - 1982. Vol. 18 no. 1-7 (Folder 38: 3)
    - 1983. Vol. 19 no. 1-3 (Folder 38: 4)
    - 1984. Vol. 20 no. 2 (Folder 38: 5)
  - International Internal Information Bulletin (SWP) (Folder 38:)
    - 1979. No. 1-3 (Folder 38: 6)
    - 1980. No. 1-4 (Folder 38: 7)
    - 1982. No. 1-3 (Folder 38: 8)
  - Party Builder (SWP) (Folder 38-39:)
    - 1944. Vol. 1 no. 1, 3 (Folder 38: 9)
    - 1945. Vol. 1 no. 4; vol. 2 no. 1-2 (Folder 38: 10)
    - 1946. Vol. 3 no. 1-2 (Folder 38: 11)
    - 1947. Vol. 4 no. 1-2 (Folder 38: 12)
    - 1970. Vol. 4 [sic] no. 1; vol. 6 no. 2-6 (Folder 38: 13)
    - 1972. Vol. 7 no. 1-7 (Folder 39: 1)
    - 1974. Vol. 8 no. 1-5 (Folder 39: 2)
    - 1975. Vol. 9 no. 1-2 (Folder 39: 3)
  - Party Organizer (SWP) (Folder 39:)
    - 1977. Vol. 1 no. 3 (Folder 39: 4)
    - 1979. Vol. 3 no. 3-7 (Folder 39: 5)
    - 1980. Vol. 4 no. 1-5 (Folder 39: 6)
    - 1981. Vol. 5 no. 1-5 (Folder 39: 7)
    - 1982. Vol. 6 no. 1 (Folder 39: 8)
    - 1983. Vol. 7 no. 1 (Folder 39: 9)
  - Party Campaigner (SWP). 1963. October no. 1 (Folder 39: 10)
  - City Convention Internal Bulletin (SWP New York Local). 1939. No. 1-2 (Folder 39: 11)
  - City Convention Bulletin (SWP New York Local) (Folder 39:)
    - 1939. No. 2 (Folder 39: 12)
    - 1942. No. 1-3 (Folder 39: 13)
  - Bulletin of Women's Committee (SWP New York Local). 1943. No. 1 (Folder 39: 14)
  - Internal Bulletin (SWP Los Angeles Local). 1952. No. 1 (Folder 39: 15)
  - Discussion Bulletin (SWP Los Angeles Local) (Folder 39:)
    - 1976. No. 1 (Folder 39: 16)
    - 1977. Vol. 2 no. 1 (Folder 39: 17)
  - Discussion Bulletin (California SWP). 1982. Vol. 1 no. 1-7 (Folder 40: 1)
  - Discussion Bulletin (SWP Northern California Bay Area District). 1983. No. 1-2, 4-6 (Folder 40: 2)
  - Catalogs and indexes for SWP internal bulletins (1939-1978), New International and International Socialist Review (1934-1960), and The Militant (1971) (Folder 40: 3)
  - Young Marxist (SWP youth bulletin) (Folder 40: 4-5)
    - 1948. Vol. 1 no. 1 (Folder 40: 4)
    - 1949. Fall (Folder 40: 5)
  - Left Wing Bulletin (Young Socialist League Left Wing Caucus). 1957. Vol. 1 no. 5 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Young Socialist Forum (Young Socialist Alliance) (Folder 40: 7-8)
    - 1958. Vol. 1 no. 3-4 (Folder 40: 7)
    - 1960. Vol. 4 no. 1 (Folder 40: 8)
  - International Information Bulletin (Young Socialist Alliance) (Folder 40: 9-10)
    - 1966. Vol. 1 no. 1 (Folder 40: 9)
    - 1969. No. 1, 3 (Folder 40: 10)
  - Discussion Bulletin (Young Socialist Alliance) (Folder 40-41:)
    - 1965. Unnumbered issue (Folder 40: 11)
    - 1973. Vol. 17 no. 1, 4-11 (Folder 41: 1)
    - 1974. Vol. 18 no. 1-8 (Folder 41: 2)
    - 1982. Vol. 26 no. 1 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Internal Information Bulletin (Young Socialist Alliance). 1974. No. 1 (Folder 41: 4)
  - Information Bulletin (International Secretariat of the Fourth International). 1959. Vol. 1 no. 22-24, 27; vol. 2 no. 1 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Internal Bulletin (International Secretariat of the Fourth International). 1959. September (Folder 41: 6)
  - International Bulletin (International Committee of the Fourth International). 1961. No. 6 (Folder 41: 7)
  - Discussion Bulletin (League for Socialist Action/Ligue Socialiste Ouvrière [Canada]). 1972. No. 5 (Folder 41: 8)
  - Bulletin of Marxist Studies (Pioneer Publishers). Undated. No. 1 (Folder 41: 9)
- Printed Matter, 1906-1987; 41-48 (Box 41-48: 9)
  Pamphlets, serial issues, and clippings, mostly published by the Socialist Workers Party or related organizations or presses
  - Serial issues, 1928-1977 (Folder 41-42:)
    - Militant. 1928 facsimile (vol. 1 no. 1); 1953 (vol. 17 no. 46) (Folder 41: 10)
    - Socialist Appeal. 1936 (vol. 2 no. 10, 12); 1937 (vol. 3 no. 3) (Folder 41: 11)
    - Socialist Workers Party Campaigner. 1954 (vol. 10 no. 1) (Folder 41: 12)
    - Perspectiva Mundial. 1977. Vol. 1 no. 1 (Folder 41: 13)
    - Fourth International (International Secretariat of the Fourth International) (Folder 41: 14-15)
      - 1958 (no. 4); 1959 (no. 6); 1959-60 (no. 8); 1960 (no. 9-10) (Folder 41: 14)
      - 1960-61 (no. 12); 1961 (no. 13); 1963 (no. 16-17) (Folder 41: 15)
    - Fourth International (International Committee of the Fourth International). 1964. Vol. 1 no. 2 (Folder 42: 1)
    - Workers International News (Revolutionary Communist Party [Great Britain]). 1945 (vol. 6 no. 2); 1946 (vol. 6 no. 5) (Folder 42: 2)
    - Newsletter (London). 1957. Vol. 1 no. 27 (Folder 42: 3)
    - Labour Review (Socialist Labour League [Great Britain]) (Folder 42: 4-5)
      - 1957 (vol. 2 no. 1-2, 4, 6) (Folder 42: 4)
      - 1958 (vol. 3 no. 1, 3-5); 1959 (vol. 4 no. 3); 1960 (vol. 5 no. 3); 1962 (vol. 7 no. 2); 1962-63 (vol. 7 no. 4); 1963 (vol. 7 no. 5) (Folder 42: 5)
    - Miscellaneous. Dialectics (1937 no. 3); International African Opinion (1939 vol. 1 no. 7); Voice of Korea (1944 vol. 1 no. 18, 23); Monthly Review (1961 vol. 13 no. 3/4); Granma (1968 vol. 3 no. 34) (Folder 42: 6)
  - Pamphlets issued by the Socialist Workers Party or affiliated organizations or presses, 1930-1986 (Folder 42-45:)
    - Breitman, George (Albert Parker). The Assassination of Malcolm X; Defend the Negro Sailors; How a Minority Can Change Society; Jim Crow Murder of Mr. and Mrs. Harry T. Moore; Negroes in the Postwar World; The New Radicalization; Race Prejudice; The Struggle for Negro Equality; Wartime Crimes of Big Business (Folder 42: 7)
    - Burnham, James (John West). How to Fight War?; Let the People Vote on War!; The People's Front; War and the Workers (Folder 42: 8)
    - Camejo, Peter. Allende's Chile; Liberalism, Ultraleftism or Mass Action (Folder 42: 9)
    - Cannon, James P. American Stalinism and Anti-Stalinism; America's Road to Socialism; The Coming American Revolution; Defense Policy in the Minneapolis Trial; The End of the Comintern; Eugene V. Debs; the I.W.W.; Leon Trotsky; The Revolutionary Party; The Road to Peace; The Russian Revolution; Socialism and Democracy; The Workers and the Second World War (Folder 42: 10)
    - Castro, Fidel. Castro Speaks on Unemployment; Fidel Castro Denounces Bureaucracy and Sectarianism; The Road to Revolution in Latin America; Women and the Cuban Revolution (Folder 42: 11)
    - Goldman, Albert. The Assassination of Leon Trotsky; In Defense of Socialism; What Is Socialism?; Why We Defend the Soviet Union (Folder 43: 1)
    - Halstead, Fred. Antiwar GIs Speak Out; The 1985-86 Hormel Meat-Packers Strike in Austin, Minnesota (Folder 43: 2)
    - Hansen, Joseph. Father Coughlin, Fascist Demagogue; In Defense of the Cuban Revolution; Nixon's Moscow and Peking Summits; The Socialist Workers Party; The Theory of the Cuban Revolution; Too Many Babies? (Folder 43: 3)
    - Macdonald, Dwight. Fascism and the American Scene; Jobs Not Battleships!; The War's Greatest Scandal (Folder 43: 4)
    - Mandel, Ernest. An Introduction to Marxist Economic Theory; The Marxist Theory of Alienation; The Marxist Theory of the State; Peaceful Coexistence and World Revolution; Revolutionary Strategy in the Imperialist Countries (Folder 43: 5)
    - Morrow, Felix. The Civil War in Spain; Revolution and Counter-revolution in Spain (Folder 43: 6)
    - Novack, George (William F. Warde). The Bill of Rights in Danger; Genocide against the Indians; How Can the Jews Survive?; The Long View of History; Marxism versus Neo-Anarchist Terrorism; Moscow vs. Peking; Revolutionary Dynamics of Women's Liberation; The Understanding of History; Uneven and Combined Development in History; Who Will Change the World? (Folder 43: 7)
    - Preis, Art. America's Permanent Depression; "Welfare State" or Socialism? (Folder 43: 8)
    - Reed, Evelyn. An Answer to "The Naked Ape"; Is Biology Woman's Destiny? (Folder 43: 9)
    - Roberts, Dick. China and the USA; Mideast Oil and U.S. Imperialism (Folder 43: 10)
    - Trotsky, Leon (Folder 43-44:)